<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>exp on G Chen</title>
    <link>http://gggchen.github.io/tags/exp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in exp on G Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Chen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gggchen.github.io/tags/exp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>我的 Podcast 节目收听列表</title>
      <link>http://gggchen.github.io/post/podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gggchen.github.io/post/podcast/</guid>
      <description>我收听的 Podcast 列表不完全归纳, 按照「想到哪写到哪」排序. 有次见到同学的播客应用的截屏, 和我收听的节目重合很高, 也许中文节目就那么些吧, 因此觉得收听播客关注列表大同小异. 目前使用 Overcast 和苹果自带的博客客户端收听博客, 苹果自带的客户端有收听该节目的人也收听节目推荐, 也是发现新节目的很好途径.
Aspirin FM 三个互相了解的好朋友聊天, 互相开一些玩笑. 有主题但是经常跑题但并不是缺点. 听起来很放松, 如果更新了经常把这个播客最早播放, 因为欢快又轻松. 曾经有几期讲了 A 君和 D 小姐的爱情故事, 让我大开眼界.
Blow your mind 简里里和峰哥这对伴侣太让人羡慕, 听两个人聊天很有启发性. 印象深刻的有之前的峰哥讲故事, 峰哥小本本和最近简里里的女性系列. 峰哥用数学角度解释问题, 很对我胃口又耳目一新, 简里里用心理学来解释问题, 很治愈我的心理焦虑和不安.
迟早更新 有书评, 游记, 博物馆参观体验还有个人小感悟等, 如果我要做一个播客, 这就是我想要做的播客啊. 过年的时候会有迟早过年系列, 从这个节目得到很多好书推荐, 比如枪枪推荐的《现代艺术150年》.
内核恐慌 一听再听反复收听的博客, 之前有一期两个人在编辑器巡礼中聊了 Vim 键位原理, 两种 mode 的编辑模式, 后来我再学 Vim 才上手无障碍. 后来一年才更新一期, 只好把历史节目拿出来反复收听.
字谈字畅 讲了很多字体排印设计相关的话题, 培养了我一些字体美感的认识, 让我自己也买了平头笔, 试着自己练一练英语的书法. 后来我非参数统计学到了样条(Spline), 很惊奇地发现计算机字母形状的保存是靠样条来做的.
其他一些推荐语简短一些, 但是同样有趣的播客:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Ocenaudio</title>
      <link>http://gggchen.github.io/post/ocenaudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gggchen.github.io/post/ocenaudio/</guid>
      <description>Oceanaudio is a good and beautiful software to edit audio documents. But recently, ocenaudio on my Macbook is very unstable, the sound it plays is too strange, just like somepeople talk with her/his mounth closed.
I&amp;rsquo;v tried substitutes to ocenaudio, like Audacity and Ardour, but UI of Audacity is bad designed and Ardour 5 is for people to record and edit, not for me.
I finally fixed the problem on my Ocenaudio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warning on Replace Broken iPhone Screen</title>
      <link>http://gggchen.github.io/post/iphone-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gggchen.github.io/post/iphone-screen/</guid>
      <description>Most articles describe replacement of iPhone screen or battery cells as easy, something to repair a Thinkpad person computer. but they fail to underline the possible risk.
I changed my iPhone 6s broken screen this month but failed. I bought a new screen along with a repair kit from Amazon.
I was excited once I received the package because I envision I could say goodbye to this broken screen and have a brand new iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>